Many of us wear trainers, or sneakers as they are called in American English.
我们很多人都穿运动鞋，也就是美式英语中被称为sneakers的鞋子。
They might not seem like anything special, but these items of footwear have become an obsession for some people.
它们可能看起来没什么特别的，但一些人十分痴迷这些鞋子。
Get ready to meet the sneakerheads.
准备好认识一下运动鞋爱好者吧。
From their beginnings as practical footwear for athletes, trainers or sneakers have become big business.
从最初作为运动员的实用鞋子开始，运动鞋已经成为了大生意。
They are now a massive part of the global fashion industry, and the sneaker market could be worth $120bn by 2026.
它们现在占全球时尚产业的比重极大，到2026年，运动鞋市场可能价值1200亿美元。
Trainers started to gain cultural cachet in the 1970s due to the popularity of basketball and football in US and UK youth culture, says fashion gallery curator Ligaya Salazar.
时尚画廊策展人利加娅·萨拉查尔表示，由于篮球和足球在美英青年文化中的普及，运动鞋在20世纪70年代开始获得文化声望。
Celebrity endorsements from the likes of Run DMC and Michael Jordan boosted the market through the 1980s and 90s.
说唱组合Run DMC和迈克尔·乔丹等名人的代言在20世纪80年代和90年代推动了市场。
Brendan Dunne, host of a podcast dedicated to sneakers, describes how, as they became cooler and more expensive, sneakers became status signifiers.
一个专门讨论运动鞋的播客主持人布伦丹·邓恩描述了运动鞋是如何随着变得更酷、更贵而成为身份和地位的象征的。
While most trainers are made for the mass market, limited-edition pairs are made to appeal to those who are looking for something special.
虽然大多数运动鞋是为大众市场生产的，但限量版鞋款是为了吸引那些寻找特别之物的人而制造的。
Sneakerheads are those who collect rare trainers, sometimes paying thousands of dollars for a pair.
运动鞋爱好者就是那些收集稀有运动鞋的人，有时会为一双鞋支付数千美元。
Dunne compares it to art collecting, pointing out that they have been sold by major auction houses and are seen by some as an investment.
邓恩将其比作艺术收藏，指出它们已被主要拍卖行出售，并被一些人视为是一种投资。
Trainer manufacturers have seen this market for rare sneakers as a good business opportunity and have teamed up with celebrities to produce limited edition pairs.
运动鞋制造商已将这一稀有运动鞋市场视为一个良好的商业机会，并与名人合作生产限量版鞋款。
This feeds into the resale market for this footwear.
这促进了这种鞋类的转手交易。
Some sneakerheads spend hours camping outside shops to get their hands on the most desirable limited editions which they can then flip for a huge profit.
一些运动鞋爱好者会花数小时在商店外露营，只为得到最令人渴望的限量版，然后可以转手卖出以获取巨大利润。
So, an item that started as an everyday functional object for people playing sports can now also be a high-fashion item worth thousands of dollars.
所以，一个最初作为人们进行体育运动时的日常功能性物品，现在也可以成为价值数千美元的高级时尚单品。